BONIFACE MACHARIA MWANGI

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER / JAVASCRIPT ENTHUSIAST

Phone: +254 700 618822 • Email: mboniface107@gmail.com • https://linkedin.com/in/bonificial

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer who is performance-driven and self-motivated, with extensive knowledge in a wide range of front-end and back-end technologies, responsive frameworks, databases, and best code practices. With over 7 years of experience, I am dedicated to participating in all phases of application development. I am also a lively debater at the planning table and a passionate agile collaborator who understands that the team only succeeds when everyone works together. I am enthusiastic about developing distributed systems and interactive user interfaces that harness the powers of JavaScript. My intellectual curiosity drives my commitment to skill development and lifelong learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PlayHT Ltd, United Arab Emirates Remote Full-Stack Software Engineer

September 2021 – To Date

- Developing software components and unit tests.
- Implementing new features based on business requirements.
- Utilised NextJS to migrate the website's from plain HTML files to Framework based site based on shareable components.
- Collaborating with a team of developers and product managers.
- Developing and maintaining quality software product code.
- Troubleshooting, debugging and upgrading software.
- Building scalable software solutions.
- Assisting in enhancing existing software components and adding new features.

Owera Ltd, Zurich, Switzerland / Surat, India Remote Full-Stack Web Developer / Development Lead

Jun 2020 - July 2021

- Started out as a backend developer where I developed schemas and proposed foundational database structure for the Freelance Marketplace Application Owera.
- Developed backend in PHP using the Slim Request/Response Framework
- Utilized React JS, CSS3 and SaSS to produce interfaces for the product, which was a freelance marketplace website.
- Built reusable components to be used then and in future by the company's development team.
- Successfully led the designing of the application database and created APIs that served the front-end with JSON data.
- Crafted a Calendar Plugin with the ability to select and highlight time periods in 15-minute intervals through Vanilla JS, JQUERY and React JS
- In general, I achieved a milestone of promoting code re-usability by building more than 30 web pages and 125+ reusable components in React JS, styled components and Sass.
- Achieved to deliver responsive, cross-browser compatible application React components which enhanced the page loading times and reduced resource heaviness by 30%.

Hope Worldwide Kenya, Nairobi, Kenya

Jan 2018 – May 2020

React Native App Developer / Full-stack Developer and Support Assistant / Development Lead

- Led a team of 5 developers through the Agile Development process from start to finish of the app development, and ensured delivery in 4 months.
- Formulated infrastructure, toolset, and deployment pipelines for supporting API development.
- Delivered clean user interface screens for the app's different features (React Native) and Web Dashboard in PHP Backend and HTML5 with Bootstrap Frontend.
- Mentored the HWWK staff on Data Management which facilitated their award of National Data Innovation Excellence Award.
- Architected solutions to business and technical problems that used the then current technologies.
- Developed KIS System (Key Populations Information System) available at https://kis.hopewwkenya.org/ and trained personnel on the use of the KIS system.
- Spearheaded transition from LAMP stack to MERN (Mongo, Epress, React, NodeJS) stack, reducing latency by 40% and increasing database admin effectiveness by 20%.
- Proposed the development of an Android based Health Educational / Social App dubbed BIGAT to be part of HWWK's intervention in promoting safe social environments and health awareness.
- As a lead developer and a member of the application rollout committee, I led a team of 8 developers in the development and launch of the product using React Native for the App, Javascript & PHP for Web
- Dashboard, Nodejs for Firestore Computations, and Firestore for the messages database. The app was rolled out on Playstore in Mid 2021, and is available under the name "BIGAT".

Truweb Solutions, Nairobi, Kenya

Jan 2016 – Dec 2017

Database and Systems Support Assistant

- Proposed cutting-edge technologies to improve the Companies in house ERP and Service Delivery Systems.
- Optimized over 95 SQL procedures in the client institutions Postgres Database which improved ERP and Other systems performance by 40%.
- Contributed to the technical design and development of microservices with high availability and performance in mind.
- Guarantee services continuous deployment ability through a continuous integration workflow
- Some of the projects done during this period include development of a Student Admission System, Email Address Retrieval System, Memo Dispatch System, and Records Management System.

Parttime Freelance Projects

2018 Jan to 2018 Feb - Database and Backend Developer, Outspan Hospital Nyeri

- Contributed in the design, development, and rollout of a Patient and Clinical Data Management System..
- Achieved the successful integration of APIs from local Payment Systems such as M-PESA and Easy Pay Equity into other existing clinical systems.

2018 June to 2018 Dec – React Native / Backend Developer, Kirana Android Inventory System with Barcode Scanner

- Solely developed a prototyping app meant for Inventory Management using Android.
- Achieved to deliver a Barcode detector using React Native and the Android Device Camera for image capture.

Realtime and Firestore Database were used, and NodeJS for the Backend.

2018 August to 2019 Jan – Fullstack / Android Developer - Quickeats Fast Food Ordering and Delivery App

- Managed the development project for a fast-food ordering and delivery app. Quickeats
- Designed the Applications backend in PHP and Postgres DB and MongoDB for the Chat Application

2019 Jan to 2019 June - Fullstack / React Native Developer - mKIS Mobile App

• Developed, designed, and delivered a mobile app version of the KIS mobile Application for Hope Worldwide Kenya, in 6 Months.

General Development Services

- Designed More than 65 Websites for different purposes like hospitality, ecommerce, catering, construction, upholstery and many more.
- Actively maintaining more than 20 websites, and 10 Applications.
- Numerous Restful APIs for existing backend systems.
- Consultancy services in Web and Application Development and Design.

EDUCATION

Karatina University, Karatina, Kenya Bachelors of Science in Information Technology	Sep 2019
Karatina University, Karatina, Kenya Diploma in Information Technology	Nov 2015
Inooro Secondary School, Nanyuki, Kenya Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education	Nov 2011

SKILLS

- JavaScript React JS / React Native /jQuery /VueJS / Vanilla / Redux /NextJS
- Backend Development NodeJS / PHP
- Dev-ops AWS / Amazon S3 / MS Azure / GCP / Heroku / Docker
- Databases Realtime Firebase / Firestore / Postgres / MySQL / MongoDB
- Collaboration Tools Git / Jira / Postman / Slack
- Video / Chat Integrations Twilio API / Zoom API / WebRTC / PeerJS / SimplePeer JS

Referees

The ICT Manager, Owera Ltd
Kheni Bhavik +91 99249 88382,
Surat,
Lazarus K Mwangi
kheni.bhavik@gmail.com
Box 183 – Nanyuki 0714210445
samulandprojects@yaho.com

The ICT Manager

Hope Worldwide Kenya

The CEO, Truweb Solutions Ltd

Nelson Ndirangu

Jonah Ngarama

0723 267099

Box 54116 (00200) - Nairobi

Ndirangu.kimiti@hopewwkenya.org

0716330450/0702332796

truweb@icthub.co.ke